Guide to the Peter Palmquist Cased Photographs Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Unidentified Subjects by Unidentified Photographers, 1840-69; Series IV; (16 items)
  - SINGLE INDIVIDUALS
    - Men
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a man, circa 1858-59 (Box 32, Folder 290)
        Sixth-plate clear-glass ambrotype with asphaltum/varnish backing with scrap of black paper behind image; no seal
        Full leather case with Birds and the Fountain motif (Rinhart #93)
      - Tintype in a case, of a man, circa 1860 (Box 33, Folder 291)
        Sixteenth-plate tintype; unsealed
        Full thermoplastic case with Scroll motif (Krainik #649); printed on paper lining-"GENUINE / UNION CASE, / IMPROVED. / Fine Gilt and Burnished / Hinge. / Scovill Mf'g Co."
      - Tintype in a case, of a man, circa 1860 (Box 33, Folder 292)
        Full brown thermoplastic case with Scroll and Geometric motif (Krainik #503); printed on paper lining, "GENUINE UNION CASE, / IMPROVED. / Fine Gilt and Burnished- / ed Hinge. / S. PECK's PATENT. / OCT 3d, 1854. / H. HALVERSON'S PATENT. / AUG. 7th, 1855, / Assigned to S. Peck."
      - Tintype in a case, of a man, circa 1860 (Box 33, Folder 293)
        Full brown thermoplastic case with the Agrarian motif (Krainik #375); printed on paper lining, "GENUINE / UNION CASE, / IMPROVED. / Fine Gilt and Burnished / Hinge. / Scovill Mf'g Co."
      - Tintype in a pin of a man, circa 1860 (Box 33, Folder 294)
        2.5 cm x 3.5 cm oval tintype
        Pin with rotating plate holder to display two plates
      - Tintype not in a case, of a man with a bicycle, circa 1860-69 (Box 33, Folder 295)
        Quarter-plate tintype; modern seal
      - Tintype in a case, of a man holding a bouquet of flowers, circa 1860-69 (Box 33, Folder 296)
        Sixth-plate hand-tinted tintype; unsealed
        Full papier-mache case with geometric medallion in center
      - Tintype in a case, of a man, circa 1865 (Box 33, Folder 297)
        Full brown thermoplastic case with Scroll and Floral motif (Krainik #469); printed on paper lining, "GENUINE / UNION CASE, / IMPROVED. / Fine Gilt and Burnished / Hinge. / Scovill Mf'g Co."
  - COUPLES
    - Infant and Adult
      - Daguerreotype in a half case of an infant and woman, circa 1850 (Box 33, Folder 298)
      - Daguerreotype in a case of an infant and woman, circa 1850-55 (Box 33, Folder 299)
      - Daguerreotype not in a case, of an older infant and woman, circa 1850-59 (Box 33, Folder 300)
      - Ambrotype in a half case of an infant and woman, circa 1858 (Box 34, Folder 301)
      - Tintype not in a case of an infant and man, circa 1858 (Box 34, Folder 302)
    - Children
      - Daguerreotype in a case of two girls, circa 1850-60 (Box 34, Folder 303)
      - Ambrotype in a case of two girls, circa 1855-60 (Box 34, Folder 304)
        Sixth-plate partially over painted clear-glass ambrotype backed with black velvet cloth; unsealed
        Full pigskin case with elaborate hinge
        Five small locks of hair behind image, three blonde and two brunette
      - Ambrotype in a half case of a girl and a boy, circa 1856 (Box 34, Folder 305)
        Sixth-plate clear-glass ambrotype in relievo with asphaltum backing; no seal
        Fragment of magazine subscription receipt from a periodical agent named Mershon, Woodville, Mississippi, behind image
    - Child and Adult
      - Ambrotype in a half case of a boy and a woman, circa 1855 (Box 34, Folder 306)
      - Ambrotype in a case of an exterior portrait of a girl and a woman, circa 1860 (Box 34, Folder 307)
        Sixth-plate ambrotype, metal backing
        Full papier-mache case; loose mat stamped, "COOKE AND EMERSON'S. PATENT APPLIED FOR / PROVIDENCE R.I."
        Woman is on extreme right side of frame
      - Tintype not in a case, of a boy and a woman, circa 1860-69 (Box 34, Folder 308)
    - Women
      - Daguerreotype in a case of two women, circa 1850-60 (Box 34, Folder 309)
      - Daguerreotype in a half case of two women, circa 1850-60 (Box 34, Folder 310)
        Etched on the verso, "Jean & Ralph / New Holland / 1772"
      - Tintype in a case of two women, circa 1856-57 (Box 35, Folder 311)
        Full thermoplastic case with Sir Roger de Coverly and the Gypsies motif (Krainik #29); printed on paper lining, "A.P. CRITCHLOW & CO., / Manufacturers of / Daguerreotype Cases. / A.P.C. & CO. / Are the Original Inventors of / the Composition for the Union Case, / (so called,) including all the various shades / of color and fineness of texture pecu- / liar to their manufacture and of the / EMBRACING RIVETED HINGES, thus / securing them from breaking out as / do others that are inserted / with or without a / metal brace./ Hinge Patented / OCT. 14, 1856, & APRIL 21, 1857"
      - Tintype in a case of two women, 1859 Jul 26 (Box 35, Folder 312)
        Full leather case with the Rose Cameo motif (Rinhart #129)
        Pencil inscription on label, "July 26th, 1859"
    - Men
      - Daguerreotype in a case of two men, circa 1850-60 (Box 35, Folder 313)
        Cover, black lacquer with mother-of-pearl inlay; back, black leather with gold pattern imprint
      - Wet collodion process on leather of two men, circa 1860 (Box 35, Folder 314)
    - Woman and Man
      - Daguerreotype in a half case of a woman and a man, circa 1850 (Box 35, Folder 315)
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a woman and a man, circa 1855 (Box 35, Folder 316)
        Half-plate ambrotype; modern seal
        Full leather case with leaf scroll design
      - Ambrotype not in a case, of a woman and a man, circa 1855-60 (Box 52, Folder 317)
        Sixth-plate ambrotype, broken plate
      - Daguerreotype in a case of a woman and a man, circa 1857 (Box 35, Folder 318)
        Full leather case with the Romanesque Urn motif (See Rinhart #141)
        Typewritten note on paper in case, "A Husband and Wife / friends of Mr. and Mrs. Joseph Hamlin"
  - GROUPS
    - Ambrotype in a case of a two girls, a boy, and a woman, circa 1850-59 (Box 35, Folder 319)
      Quarter-plate hand-tinted clear-glass ambrotype with asphaltum/varnish backing; unsealed
      Full brown thermoplastic case with the Sweet Potato Dinner motif (Krainik #17); printed on paper lining, "LITTLEFIELD, PARSONS & CO., / Successors to A.P. Critchlow & Co. / MANUFACTURERS OF / Daguerreotype Cases. / L., P. & Co., are the sole / Proprietors and only legal / Manufacturers of / Union Cases, / With the Embracing Riveted Hinge. / Patented / Oct. 14, 1856, & April 21, 1857."
    - Ambrotype with a horizontal orientation in a case of three girls, circa 1855 (Box 35, Folder 320)
      Half-plate hand-tinted clear-glass ambrotype with asphaltum backing in relievo; no seal
      Full leather case with grape motif
    - Ambrotype in a case of sixteen women and four men, circa 1855 (Box 36, Folder 321)
      Half-plate ambrotype; unsealed
      Full leather case with variant of Spray of Roses motif (Rinhart #131)
    - Ambrotype in a half case of three women, circa 1855-60 (Box 36, Folder 322)
    - Ambrotype in a case of five girls, circa 1857 (Box 36, Folder 323)
      Quarter-plate clear-glass ambrotype in relievo
      Inscription on paper slip behind image, "Presented March 21st, 1857"
    - Ambrotype with a horizontal orientation in a case of an infant, six girls, a boy, and a woman, circa 1857 (Box 36, Folder 324)
      Half-plate clear-glass ambrotype with asphaltum backing; unsealed
    - Tintype with no case of a woman, girl, and boy, circa 1858 (Box 36, Folder 325)
    - Ambrotype in a case of a boy, three women, and a man, circa 1858 (Box 36, Folder 326)
      Full thermoplastic case with Daniel in the Lions' Den motif (Krainik #38); printed on paper lining, "LITTLEFIELD, PARSONS & CO., / Successors to A.P. Critchlow & Co. / MANUFACTURERS OF / Daguerreotype Cases. / L., P. & Co., are the sole / Proprietors and only legal / Manufacturers of / Union Cases, / With the Embracing Riveted Hinge. / Patented / Oct. 14, 1856, & April 21, 1857."
    - Ambrotype in a case of five women and three men, identified as probably a walking excursion party in a traveling ambrotypist wagon, circa 1858 (Box 36, Folder 327)
      Quarter-plate clear-glass ambrotype with a sheet of ruby glass behind; modern seal
      Full papier-mache case, unhinged, with floral design
    - Two tintypes in the same case of two girls and a boy and an infant with a man and a woman, circa 1860 (Box 36, Folder 328)
      Half-plate tintypes; no seal
      Full double leather case with floral bouquet motif
    - Tintype in a frame, of three men, circa 1860 (Box 53, Folder 329)
      Quarter-plate ferrotype; unsealed
    - Tintype not in a case, of three women posed sewing, circa 1860 (Box 36, Folder 330)
      Blindstamp on left side of mat, "COOKE & EMERSON'S PATENT APPLIED FOR"; blindstamp on right side of mat, "PROVIDENCE R.I."
    - Tintype not in a case, of two infants and an obscured woman, circa 1860 (Box 37, Folder 331)
      Blindstamp on left side of mat, "DEAN & EMERSON PATENT APPLIED FOR"; blindstamp on right side of mat, "WORCESTER, MASS. No. 29"
    - Ambrotype in a half case of an exterior portrait of an infant, two women, and two men, circa 1860 (Box 37, Folder 332)
      Sixth-plate clear-glass ambrotype with asphaltum backing, backed with iron sheet; no seal
  - OBJECTS
    - Ambrotype in a case of an engraving of a man, probably originally created circa 1780-1800, circa 1850-59 (Box 37, Folder 333)
      Sixth-plate clear-glass ambrotype with brown velvet backing; no seal
      Full pigskin case with simple scroll motif
    - Two ambrotypes in the same case, copies of paintings depicting a man and a woman, circa 1855 (Box 37, Folder 334)
      Quarter-plate clear-glass ambrotype with asphaltum backing; unsealed with black velvet behind
      Double thermoplastic case with the Washington Monument, Richmond, Virginia (Krainik #21); imprinted on case lining: "GENUINE / UNION CASE, / IMPROVED. / Fine Gilt and Burnished / Hinge / S. PECK & Co., / MANUFACTURERS."
      Image of man extremely deteriorated
    - Ambrotype in a case, a copy of a daguerreotype of a woman, circa 1857 (Box 37, Folder 335)
- Cased Photograph Components, 1844-69; Series V; (22 items)
  Series V., Cased Photographs Components, consists of items involved in the construction of cased photographs, and is comprised primarily of cases and mats. It is organized into four subseries.
  The first subseries, Cases by Identified Manufacturers, is alphabetically organized according to the manufacturer.
  The second subseries, Cases by Unidentified Manufacturers, and third subseries, Case Covers by Unidentified Manufacturers, are organized chronologically by apparent manufacture date.
  The fourth subseries, Mats, consists of mats organized according to their manufacturer, followed by mats by unidentified manufacturers.
  - CASES BY IDENTIFIED MANUFACTURERS
    - A. P. Critchlow and Company
      Northhampton, Massachusetts
      - Case with no image, 1856 (Box 37, Folder 336)
        Full ninth-plate thermoplastic case with Geometric motif (Krainik #461); printed in paper backing, "A.P. CRITCHLOW & CO., / Manufacturers of / Daguerreotype Cases. / A.P.C. & CO. / Are the Original Inventors of / the Composition for the Union Case, / (so called,) including all the various shades / of color and fineness of texture pecu- / liar to their manufacture and of the / EMBRACING RIVETED HINGES, thus / securing them from breaking out as / do others that are inserted / with or without a / metal brace. / Hinge Patented / OCT. 14, 1856."
      - Case with no image, 1857 (Box 37, Folder 337)
        Full quarter-plate thermoplastic case with the Sir Roger de Coverly and the Gypsies motif (Krainik #29 and #30); printed in paper backing, "A.P. CRITCHLOW & CO., / Manufacturers of / Daguerreotype Cases. / A.P.C. & CO. / Are the Original Inventors of / the Composition for the Union Case, / (so called,) including all the various shades / of color and fineness of texture pecu- / liar to their manufacture and of the / EMBRACING RIVETED HINGES, thus / securing them from breaking out as / do others that are inserted / with or without a / metal brace. / Hinge Patented / OCT. 14, 1856."
    - Littlefield, Parsons & Company
      Northampton, Massachusetts, Florence, Massachusetts, or New York, New York
      - Case with no image, circa 1858 (Box 37, Folder 338)
        Full brown thermoplastic case with the Beehive, Grain, and Farm Tools motif (Krainik #121); printed on paper lining, "Littlefield, Parson & Co., / MANUFACTURERS OF / Daguerreotype Cases. / L., P. & Co., are the sole / Proprietors and only legal Manu- / facturers of UNION CASES, with the / Embracing Riveted Hinge, / Patented October 14, 1856, / and April 21, 1857."
      - Case with no image, circa 1858 (Box 37, Folder 339)
        Full ninth-plate octagon double-image thermoplastic case with the Chess Player motif on both front and back covers (Krainik #580); printed on paper lining, "Littlefield, Parson & Co., / MANUFACTURERS OF / Daguerreotype Cases. / L., P. & Co., are the sole / Proprietors and only legal Manu- / facturers of UNION CASES, with the / Embracing Riveted Hinge, / Patented October 14, 1856, / and April 21, 1857.
    - Samuel Peck and Company
      - Case with no image, 1856-57 (Box 37, Folder 340)
        Full brown thermoplastic case that holds four sixteenth-plate images, with Wildflowers motif (Krainik #575); printed on paper lining, "GENUINE / UNION CASE, / IMPROVED. / Fine Gilt and Burnished / Hinge. / S. PECK & CO., / MANUFACTURERS"
      - Case with no image, 1856-57 (Box 38, Folder 341)
        Full brown thermoplastic sixth-plate case with the Deer and the Pine Tree motif (See Krainik #167); printed on paper lining, "GENUINE / UNION CASE, / IMPROVED. / Fine Gilt and Burnished / Hinge. / S. PECK & CO., / MANUFACTURERS"
    - Shew, Myron
      Philadelphia, Pennsylvania
      - Case with no image, circa 1850 (Box 38, Folder 342)
        Full sixth-plate leather case with Two Lilies motif (Rinhart #112); printed on paper lining, "MYRON SHEW, / DEALER IN / Daguerreotype Materials / No. 116 Chestnut Street, / PHILADELPHIA"
    - Shew, William
      Boston, Massachusetts
      - Case with no image, circa 1845 (Box 38, Folder 343)
        Full sixth-plate leather case with Curved Octagon with Scroll, Center motif (Rinhart #219); printed on paper lining, "WM. SHEW, / Miniature Case Maker, / And Dealer in / Plates, Lockets, Chemicals, and / German & American Cameras, / Corner of Court and Howard Sts. / BOSTON"
      - Case with no image, circa 1845 (Box 38, Folder 344)
    - Wadhams Manufacturing Company
      - Case with no image, circa 1858 (Box 38, Folder 345)
        Full ninth-plate black thermoplastic case with the Charter Oak motif (Krainik #365); printed on paper lining, "MANUFACTURED BY / WADHAMS / Manufacturing Co. / Sole Proprietors of / KINSLEY & PARKER'S / HINGE, / Patented June 1st, 1858"
  - CASES BY UNIDENTIFIED MANUFACTURERS
    - Case with no image, circa 1850-1860 (Box 38, Folder 346)
      Full sixth-plate black-lacquered case with mother-of-pearl inlay
    - Case with no image, circa 1850-1860 (Box 38, Folder 347)
      Full brown leather case with three flower bouquet in center and leaf and geometric scrolling
    - Case with no image, but includes locks of hair; outer braid made of the hair of the parents, encircling hair of children, 1860 Sep 28 (Box 38, Folder 348)
      Full leather sixth-plate case with Two Lilies motif (Rinhart #112), possibly made by Myron Shew, circa 1850
      Inscribed names identify each lock of hair (top to bottom), "Lemuel [unreadable] / George [unreadable] / Harriet [unreadable] / Charlie [unreadable] / Howard [unreadable] / Anna [unreadable] / Arthur"; annotated in ink on paper covering hair clippings, "A little keepsake from - / Hattie to Cousin George - / with the kindest wishes / from Father - Mother - and / brothers and sister - / September 28, 1860 - / Lunenburg [Nova Scotia, Canada]"
  - CASE COVERS BY UNIDENTIFIED MANUFACTURERS
    - Case cover, circa 1850-60 (Box 38, Folder 349)
      Half-plate brown leather case cover with grapevine cluster motif in center and floral scrolling
    - Case cover, circa 1850-60 (Box 38, Folder 350)
      Half-plate brown leather case cover with poppies in center and floral scrolling
    - Case cover, circa 1850-60 (Box 38, Folder 351)
      Half ninth-plate papier-mache case cover with a geometric motif
  - MATS
    - Cooke and Emerson
      Providence, Rhode Island
      - Sixth-plate mat, circa 1860-69 (Box 39, Folder 352)
        Blindstamp on left edge of mat, "COOKE & EMERSON PATENT APPLIED FOR"; blindstamp on right edge of mat, "PROVIDENCE R.I."
    - Dean and Emerson
      Worcester, Massachusetts
      - Four ninth-plate mats, one sixth-plate mat, and one quarter-plate mat, circa 1861 (Box 39, Folder 353)
    - Gennert Brothers
      New York, New York
      - One sixth-plate mat, and one ninth-plate mat, 1858-1859 (Box 39, Folder 354)
        General note
        Blindstamp right edge of mats, "NEW YORK"; blindstamp left edge of mat, "GENNERT BROS."
    - Holmes, Booth & Hayden
      Waterbury, Connecticut
      - Two ninth-plate mats, four sixth-plate mats, and one quarter-plate mat, circa 1857 (Box 39, Folder 355)
        Blindstamp left edge of mats, "HOLMES, BOOTH & HAYDEN SUPERFINE"; blindstamp right edge of mat, "WATERBURY, CONN. No. [13, 24, 26, 29, 33]"
    - Scovill Manufacturing Company
      - Three sixth-plate mats and one quarter-plate mat, circa 1860-1869 (Box 39, Folder 356)
        Blindstamp upper edge of mats, "SCOVILL MFG Co. SUPERIOR", blindstamp lower edge of mat, "WATERBURY CONN. No [823, 830, 835, and 341]"
    - Unidentified Manufacturer
      - One quarter-plate mat, circa 1850-1869 (Box 39, Folder 357)
      - One half plate mat and a metal back plate, circa 1850-1860 (Box 39, Folder 357a)
        The metal back plate includes a latent outline of a portrait of a man.
- Associated Printed Material, 1843-99; Series VI; (53 items)
  Series VI. Associated Printed Material, is arranged into four subseries: Trade Cards, arranged alphabetically by surname under headings for the states of Connecticut, Massachusetts, Maine, New Hampshire, Rhode Island, and an unidentified location; Advertising Materials, arranged chronologically; Newspaper Advertisements, arranged chornologically; and Engravings, which are based on daguerreotypes, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - TRADE CARDS
    - Connecticut
      - Ross, H. P. (Box 40, Folder 358)
        Groton Junction
    - Massachusetts
      - Appleton, William R. (Box 40, Folder 359)
        West Lynn
      - Bartlett, Pliny (Box 40, Folder 360)
      - Bell, John R. (Box 40, Folder 361)
      - Bent, Israel (Box 40, Folder 362)
      - Chapman, George D. (Box 40, Folder 363-364)
      - Cole, Charles (Box 40, Folder 365)
        Roxbury
      - Davis & Company (Box 40, Folder 366-367)
      - Eastman, W. B. (Box 40, Folder 368)
      - Fish, Addison A. & Company (Box 40, Folder 369)
        Lowell
      - Foss, George W. (Box 40, Folder 370)
      - George, B. F. (Box 40, Folder 371)
      - Heywood, John D. (Box 40, Folder 372)
      - Higgins, M. J. (Box 40, Folder 373)
      - Ives, Loyal M. and Charles H. Collagan (Box 40, Folder 374)
      - James & Company (Box 40, Folder 375-376)
      - Mitchell, George E. (Box 40, Folder 377)
      - Perry, Alexander (Box 40, Folder 378)
        Waltham
      - Rider (Box 40, Folder 379)
      - Shattuck, Sewall (Box 40, Folder 380)
      - Smith (Box 40, Folder 381)
      - Springfield Photographic Gallery (Box 40, Folder 382)
      - Walton, Daniel (Box 40, Folder 383)
        Haverhill
      - White, A. P. (Box 40, Folder 384)
      - Wyman & Company (Box 40, Folder 385)
      - Yeaw, Albion (Box 40, Folder 386)
        Lawrence
    - Maine
      - Teague, Isaac N. (Box 40, Folder 387)
        Lewiston
    - New Hampshire
      - Simons, Darwin A. (Box 40, Folder 388)
        Manchester
    - Rhode Island
      - Brown, Silas B. (Box 40, Folder 389)
        Providence
      - White, Joseph & Company (Box 40, Folder 390)
    - Unidentified Location
      - Atkinson, S. J. (Box 40, Folder 391)
  - ADVERTISING MATERIALS
    - Flier for Alexander G. Nye (Box 41, Folder 392)
      The text advertises "Daguerreotype Likenesses. Mr. A. G. Nye, will be prepared to take Daguerreotype likenesses, at the former rates, at Leyden Hall, in and After Monday next. All who may favor him with their patronage will be guarantied a perfect likeness. Plymouth [Massachusetts], June 18th, 1846"
    - Broadside for E. S. Hayden (Box 41, Folder 393)
      Text of broadside, "SPLENDID DAGUERREOTYPIST MINIATURES, TAKEN IN EVERY STYLE, BY E.S. HAYDEN, Who would respectfully inform the inhabitants of [blank space] that he has taken Rooms in [blank space] and is now prepared to take likenesses of all who may favor his with a call. His Miniatures are warranted not to be surpassed by any, for their richness of tone and life-like appearance; standing out in such bold relief, that they can be seen equally well in any light. All those wishing a perfect likeness of themselves, or their friends, would do well to call soon; confident that neither Pictures nor Price will fail to suit. Paintings and Engravings ACCURATELY COPIED. Persons are invited to call and examine Specimens."
      Printed in Waterbury, Connecticut
    - Sign that advertises "Louis N. Greenig / Photographic Parlors / 1800 & 1802 North Front St., [Philadelphia], circa 1899 (Box 41, Folder 394)
  - NEWSPAPER ADVERTISEMENTS
    - The Boston Daily Bee
      - 1843 May 23 (Box 41, Folder 395)
        Includes advertisements for photographers Albert Sands Southworth, Asa White, Plumbe's Gallery, and the partnership between George B. Parrott and C. C. Partridge
      - 1843 Aug 26 (Box 41, Folder 396)
        Includes advertisements for photographers Horatio H. Long and Plumbe's Gallery, and photographic supplies dealer P. Charrier
      - 1844 Feb 21 (Box 41, Folder 397)
        Includes advertisements for photographers Asa White and Plumbe's Gallery
      - 1844 Apr 6 (Box 41, Folder 398)
      - 1844 Jun 12 (Box 41, Folder 399)
      - 1844 Sep 17 (Box 41, Folder 400)
      - 1844 Sep 20 (Box 41, Folder 401)
      - 1845 Feb 10 (Box 41, Folder 402)
        Includes an advertisement for Plumbe's Gallery
    - Newspaper Clippings
      - F. White & Company, 1845 Nov 22 (Box 42, Folder 403)
        Possibly Dover, New Hampshire
      - Plumbe's Gallery, 1846 Jul 18 (Box 42, Folder 404)
      - Plumbe's Gallery, 1846 Jul 25 (Box 42, Folder 405)
  - ENGRAVINGS
    - Calhoun, John Caldwell, circa 1856 (Box 42, Folder 406)
      Engraving by Henry Bryan Hall from a daguerreotype by Mathew B. Brady
    - Clay, Henry, circa 1852 (Box 42, Folder 407)
      Engraving by T. Johnson from a daguerreotype by Montgomery P. Simons
    - Clay, Henry, circa 1852 (Box 42, Folder 408)
      Engraving by A. Sealey from a daguerreotype by Marcus Aurelius Root
    - Colton, Walter, circa 1840-41 (Box 42, Folder 409)
      Engraving by G. Parker from a daguerreotype by Frederick Langenheim and William Frederick Langenheim and published in Graham's Magazine, accompanied by a short biography
    - Morse, Samuel Finley Breese, circa 1872 (Box 42, Folder 410)
      Engraving by W. S. L. Jewett, possibly for Harper's Weekly, after a photograph by Mathew B. Brady
- Additions from Other Collections, Series VII
  - Daguerreotypes
    - Daguerreotype unmounted approximate twelfth plate of an indistinct studio portrait of a woman, undated (Box 55)
    - Daguerreotype unmounted ninth plate with no extant image and plate mark "30", undated (Box 55)
    - Daguerreotype unmounted sixth plate of an indistinct studio portrait of a man, undated (Box 55)